Guide to the Tamiment Library Web Collection on Labor Unions and Organizations WEB.ARC.002
Tamiment Library and Robert F. Wagner Labor Archives
- SAG-AFTRA Archived Website, Feb 25, 2012 - ongoing; SAG-AFTRA (Organization)
  The website contains information on the merger in 2012 of the Screen Actors Guild (SAG) and American Federation of Television and Radio Artists (AFTRA). It contains news related to the merger, events, frequently asked questions, and a page on merger materials.
  Television broadcasting -- Employees -- Labor unions -- United States; Motion picture industry -- Employees -- Labor unions -- United States; Actors -- Labor unions -- United States.; Radio broadcasting |x Employees |x Labor unions |z United States.
- Screen Actors Guild, New York Branch Archived Website, Mar 10, 2009 - ongoing; Screen Actors Guild. New York Branch
  The New York Branch of the Screen Actors Guild is one of twenty branches nationwide representing actors working in motion pictures, television, commercials, industrials, video games, Internet and all new media formats. The Guild exists to enhance actors working conditions, compensation and benefits and to be a powerful, unified voice on behalf of artists rights.
  Motion picture industry -- Employees -- Labor unions -- New York (State) -- New York; Actors |x Labor unions |z New York (State) |z New York.; Television broadcasting -- Employees -- Labor unions -- New York (State) -- New York
- Service Employees International Union Committee of Interns and Residents Archived Website, Apr 1, 2014-ongoing; Committee of Interns and Residents/SEIU Healthcare.
  The Service Employees International Union Committee of Interns and Residents is the largest housestaff union in the United States. It represents residents, interns and fellows in California, Florida, Massachusetts, New Jersey, New Mexico, New York, and Washington, D.C. It was founded in 1957 as the Committee of Interns and Residents to represent interns and residents in New York City hospitals. In May 1997, the Committee of Interns and Residents affiliated with the Service Employees International Union, and as of this writing [2014] represents over one million health care workers across the United States. The website contains information on benefits, alumni services, news, their magazine, "Vitals," and conference details.
  Residents (Medicine) |z United States.; Hospitals |x Employees |x Labor unions |z United States.
- Social Service Employees Union Local 371 Archived Website, Sep 25, 2007 - ongoing; Social Service Employees Union. Local 371
  Founded in 1965, Social Service Employees Union Local 371 is part of District Council 37 of the American Federation of State, County and Municipal Employees AFL-CIO (AFSCME), which represents workers employed by New York City in social service professions. The website contains information on benefits and grievance filing, and their current and past contracts.
  Social workers |z New York (State) |z New York.; Social workers |x Labor unions |z New York (State) |z New York.
- Starbucks Union (IWW) Archived Website, Jul 30, 2009 - ongoing; Starbucks Workers Union
  The Starbucks Workers Union is an organization of employees at Starbucks (a coffee chain) united for a living wage, secure work hours, and respect on the job. They are affiliated with the Industrial Workers of the World.
  Syndicalism.; Food service employees -- Labor unions -- United States.; Food service employees -- Labor unions -- United States.
- Street Vendors Mobilizing and Organizing in Solidarity Archived Website, May 6, 2012 - ongoing; Street Vendors Mobilizing and Organizing in Solidarity
  Vendedoras Ambulantes Movilizando y Organizando en Solidaridad (VAMOS Unidos or Street Vendors Mobilizing and Organizing in Solidarity) is a Bronx based social justice organization, founded in 2007 by low income Latino/Latina street vendors. The organization works to organize Latino immigrants, for economic and racial justice, immigrant rights, and police accountability. The website contains information on provided services, news, photos, and videos.
  Street vendors
- #StrikeFastFood Archived Website, Sep 5, 2014-ongoing; Fast Food Forward; Low Pay is Not OK
  In late 2014, Fast Food Forward merged with Low Pay is Not OK to form #StrikeFastFood. The organization is a movement of New York City fast food workers to raise wages and gain rights at work. They were formed after Thanksgiving 2012 from a small group of striking fast food workers. They goal is to raise the minimum wage to $15 an hour and the right to form a union without retaliation. The website contains information on past and future demonstrations and events, as well as news alerts related to the campaign.
  Restaurants |x Employees |x Labor unions.
- Transport Workers Union of America Archived Website, Sep 25, 2007 - ongoing; Transport Workers Union of America
  The Transport Workers Union of America (TWU) is a labor union that was founded in 1934 by subway workers in New York City. The TWU has four divisions: Railroad; Gaming; Airline; Transit; and Utility, University and Service. The Union has 114 autonomous locals representing over 200,000 members and retirees in 22 states around the country. The TWU is a member of the AFL-CIO and the International Transport Workers Federation (ITF). The website includes a blog, blogs related to different industries within the union, their political action committee, Committee On Political Education (COPE), their publications, TWU Express and ATD Insider, reports, conference materials, and images.
- Transport Workers Union of America Local 100 Archived Website, Sep 25, 2007 - ongoing; Transport Workers Union of America. Local 100
  Local 100 is a local of the Transport Workers Union of America. The Local primarily represents workers in the New York City public transportation system and at some private bus lines serving the New York City metropolitan area.
  Transport workers -- Labor unions -- New York (State)
- Union of Clerical, Administrative & Technical Staff, NYU Local 3882, NYSUT, AFT, AFL-CIO (UCATS) Archived Website, Sep 24, 2007 - ongoing; American Federation of Teachers. Local 3882 (Clerical Union)
  Union of Clerical, Administrative & Technical Staff, Local 3882,, NYSUT, AFT, AFL-CIO (UCATS), founded in 1978, is a labor union that represents over 1500 clerical, administrative, and technical staff at New York University. They are affiliated with the American Federation of Teachers and were formerly known as the United Staff Association of NYU. The website contains the current contract, their newsletter, Momentum, and their blog.
  Universities and colleges |x Employees |x Labor unions |z New York (State) |z New York.; Clerks |x Labor unions |z New York (State) |z New York.; Labor unions -- New York (State) -- New York -- History -- 20th century.; New York University
- UNITE HERE (Organization) Archived Website, Mar 24, 2009 - ongoing; UNITE HERE (Organization)
  UNITE HERE is the merger of two labor unions, the Union of Needletrades, Industrial and Textile Employees (UNITE) and the Hotel Employees and Restaurant Employees International Union (HERE). UNITE HERE, founded in 2004, is a labor union in the United States and Canada with more than 265,000 active members. The union's members work predominantly in the hotel, food service, laundry, warehouse, and casino gaming industries. It is currently affiliated with the AFL-CIO.
  Clothing workers |x Labor unions |z United States.; Service industries workers -- Labor unions -- United States.
- United Brotherhood of Carpenters and Joiners of America: Shop & Industrial Local 2790 Archived Website, Feb 4, 2012 - ongoing; United Brotherhood of Carpenters and Joiners of America.. Local 2790 (New York, N.Y.)
  The United Brotherhood of Carpenters Shop and Industrial Local 2790 was formed in August 2011, from the dissolution of the Architectural Woodworkers Local 2090 and Industrial Local 2870. UBC Local Union 2790 is a specialty trade union that represents carpenters, industrial shop workers, architectural woodworkers, millworkers, finish carpenters, wood finishers, cabinet installers, trim carpenters, architectural metal workers, and cabinetmakers throughout the five boroughs of New York City; as well as Long Island, New Jersey, and Westchester County. Local 2790 is part of the United Brotherhood of Carpenters & Joiners of America, and the New York City District Council of Carpenters. The website includes news listings, wages and benefits, event listings, images, and other reports.
  Carpenters -- Labor unions -- New York (State) -- New York
- United Federation of Teachers Archived Website, Sep 26, 2007 - ongoing; United Federation of Teachers
  The United Federation of Teachers (Local 2 of the American Federation of Teachers) represents more than 200,000 people, and is the sole bargaining agent for most of the non-supervisory educators who work in the New York City public schools. It represents approximately 74,000 teachers and 17,000 classroom paraprofessionals, along with school secretaries, attendance teachers, guidance counselors, psychologists, social workers, education evaluators, nurses, laboratory technicians, adult education teachers and 32,000 retired members. The UFT also represents teachers and other employees of some private educational institutions. The allied Federation of Nurses/UFT represents some 2,500 registered nurses of the New York City Visiting Nurse Service and several private New York City hospitals and health care institutions. The union led a successful organizing drive to gain collective-bargaining rights for 28,000 New York City home child-care providers in 2007. The website includes bargaining agreements, their blog, EdWize, benefits, event and news listings, and their platform.
  Teachers' unions -- New York (State) -- New York; Education -- New York (State) -- New York.
- United Food and Commercial Workers International Union (UFCW) Archived Website, Dec 3, 2009 - ongoing; United Food and Commercial Workers International Union
  The United Food and Commercial Workers International Union, founded in 1979, is a labor union representing approximately 1.3 million workers in the United States and Canada in many industries, including agriculture, health care, meatpacking, poultry and food processing, manufacturing, textile, chemical trades, and retail food. It is affiliated with the Change to Win Coalition.
  Food Industry and Trade |x Employees |x Labor Unions; Food industry and trade |x Employees|x Labor unions |z Canada.
- Utility Workers of America, Local 1-2 Archived Website, Feb 19, 2009 - ongoing; Utility Workers Union of America. Local 1-2
  Local 1-2 of the Utility Workers Union of America evolved out of the Utility Workers Organizing Committee (UWOC) established by the Congress of Industrial Organizations (CIO) in 1938. In 1946, with more than 180 locals organized nationwide, the UWOC transformed itself into the Utility Workers Union of America, CIO. Local 1-2 represents New York area with members working in the electric, gas, water, and nuclear industries across the United States. The website includes information on their political action committee, their publication, the Record, images and other audiovisual materials, news listings, and event listings.
  Electric industry workers|x Labor unions |z New York (State) |z New York.
- Whole Foods Market Workers Unite! Archived Website, Nov 15, 2014-ongoing; Whole Foods Workers Unite!
  Whole Food Workers Unite is the organizing committee to organize a union for the employees of Whole Foods Market, a national supermarket chain in the United States. The workers are fighting for higher wages, consistent scheduling, paid time off, retirement plans, the ability to work full-time for new hires, safety, and an affordable health care plan. They are affiliated with the Industrial Workers of the World (IWW).The website contains a petition and a news wire.
  Service industries workers -- Labor unions -- United States.; Whole Foods Market
- Women on the Job Archived Website, Mar 9, 2009 - Dec 24, 2012; Women on the Job
  Women on the Job (WOJ) was founded in 1981 as a private, not-for-profit advocacy organization dedicated to achieving women's equality in the workplace on Long Island. WOJ was a project of Resources for Program Development, Inc. (RPD), which had been established with funding from the North Shore Unitarian Universalist Society VEATCH Program. The WOJ program was initiated in October 1981 by co-founders Lillian McCormick and Charlotte Shapiro. Its mission was to foster equal employment opportunities for women and combat workplace discrimination against women in Long Island communities.
  Working class women -- United States.; Women labor union members -- United States.; Women in the labor movement -- United States